

# Sarah Yaa Amoah Abeka

Nutritionist & Food Scientist

🔀 sarahyaa2018@gmail.com 📞 +233559555194 💡 Tema/Ghana 🏲 Ghanaian

k https://www.sarahabeka.com/ in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarah-abeka-bb7810246

• https://medium.com/@sarahyaa2018

### **Profile**

Skilled Nutritionist and Food Scientist with proven academic and practical understanding of Micro-biology, Nutritional Physiology, Nutrients and their Metabolism, Food Analysis, Sensory Science, Nutrient Interrelationship and needs, and Thermal Processing to mention a few. I have strong sensory analytic and research experience. I respond positively to assignments, and enjoy participation in teamwork. My goal is to become a professional nutritionist. 🙀 🍳 🍴 🍽 🔪



#### Education

08.2018 - 09.2022 | Accra, Ghana

University Of Ghana 🛮

Chemistry, Biology & Physics, Holy Child High School

05.2014 - 10.2018 | Cape Coast, Ghana

## **Professional Experience**

**Sensory Analyst Trainee,** Department of Nutrition and Food Science, University of Ghana 🛮

01.2022 - present | Legon/Accra, Ghana

• Responsible for analyzing and characterizing food product

# Nutrition Counselor (Internship), Tema General Hospital □

06.2021 - 08.2021 | Tema, Ghana

- Obtain and analyze patients' dietary history
- Asses patients' eating habit and pattern
- Counselling patients and advising them on the best and suitable nutritional practices
- Regular monitoring of patients' status

## Regulatory Officer (National Service Personnel),

Accra, Ghana

Food and Drugs Authority 🗷

- Assessed residents in a long term care (LTC) and skilled nursing setting for nutrition risk and applied medical nutrition therapies accordingly, such as intervention with oral supplements
- Lead weekly meetings on a QAPI initiative for prevention of excessive weight loss
- · Applied medical nutrition therapies to nutrition problems in the acute care setting
- Conducted inservices and audits for the dietary department to ensure food safety compliance

#### **Skills**

Sales	Inspection	Nutrition counseling	Research
Microsoft Excel	Microsoft Powerpoint	<b>Minitab</b> Statistical Data Analytics tool	
Languages			
Twi	• • • •	English	• • • • •
Interests			
• Cooking	• Reading	• Listening to music	

#### References

**Dr. Fredrick vuvor**, University Of Ghana fvuvor@ug.edu.gh, +233(244698344)

**Dr. Maame Yaakwah Blay-Adjei**, University Of Ghana mybadjei@ug.edu.gh, +233(545525974)

**Dr. Bennett Atta Dzandu**, University Of Ghana badzandu@ug.edu.gh, +233(0504714855)

Prof M. Steiner-Asiedu

tillysteiner@gmail.com, +233(0541260794

**Dr. Angela Parry-Hanson**, University Of Ghana aparry-hanson@ug.edu.gh, +233(0272715759)

**Prof. Esther Sakyi-Dawson**, University Of Ghana esakyid@ug.edu.gh, +233(244367242)

**Dr. Hussein Mohammad**, University Of Ghana hmohammed@ug.edu.gh, +233(0559369505)

## **Projects**

## Academic research (Undergraduate), Exporing the gaps in

sensory and consumer science education and industry practice

in selected food companies in Ghana -

I completed a research project in 2022 Exploring the gaps in sensory and consumer science education and industry practice in selected food companies in Ghana. This study aims to explore the knowledge gaps between what students are taught and how they apply this knowledge in industry. The study was done by administering a semi-structured questionnaire using one-on-one interviews and online surveys to students, lecturers, and staff of food companies.

Download full documentation with this link 👉 https://www.sarahabeka.com/Finalyearproject.pdf 🗷

10.2022